Guide to the Records of the City of Danbury 1889-1933 DRG 2 DRG 2
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Danbury (City of) Records
1889-1933
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
City of Danbury, Conn.
DRG 2
4.25 Linear Feet, 7 boxes
A small collection of Danbury city records. Includes city clerk correspondence and City Council minutes from the early establishment of the City of Danbury. Also includes: Tax anticipation ledgers.
Provenance
Aquired by Dr. Warner and Janick and donated to the Archive.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
According to Section 3-3 of City of Danbury Charter: "The City Clerk shall be the Clerk of the Council. The City Clerk shall keep for public inspection copies of every proposed ordinance and a record of all proceedings including all roll call votes. All records so kept shall be authenticated by such Clerk or the President of the Council or both. The Clerk shall be responsible for the publication of such notices of hearing and publication of ordinances as may be necessary and perform such other duties as the Council may determine. The Council may, at any time, appoint an Assistant Clerk or Clerks, who shall, in the absence or disability of the Clerk, perform all the duties of the Clerk, and all records and acts of said Assistant shall have the same validity as the records and acts of the Clerk."
According to Section 3-1 of City of Danbury Charter on the city council: "There shall be a Council consisting of twenty-one members, as provided in Section 2-2, which shall be vested with the legislative power of the City, hereinafter referred to as the Common Council. The members of the Common Council shall be compensated in an amount which will defray reasonable expenses incurred in performing their duties subject to provisions of Section 7-460 of the General Statutes, as amended. Such compensation shall be determined by the preceding Common Council."
Scope and Content Note
This is a small collection of Danbury city records. Includes City Clerk correspondence and City Council (or Common Council) minutes from the early establishment of the City of Danbury. Also includes: Tax anticipation ledgers.
Originally, materials were assigned to separate collections in under a general record category of City/Town of Danbury Records. The collection was reorganized so that City records and Town records were collected together and assigned to series either within City of Danbury Records of Town of Danbury Records. The original accession numbers are listed in the inventory.
Related Material
Town of Danbury Records
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically within series.
The files are grouped into 3 series:
Series I: City Council Meetings, 1889-1904
Series II: City Clerk - Correspondence, 1897-1906
Series III: Tax Anticipation Notes, 1933
Correspondence.; Danbury (Conn.) -- History.; Danbury (Conn.); Ledgers (account books).; Office of City Clerk. City of Danbury.
- Series I: City Council Meetings, 1889-1904
  General note
  Acc #162-1976
  - July 15, 1889 to February 2, 1894, 1889-1894 (Box 1, Ledger 1)
  - March 10, 1894 to February 24, 1904, 1894-1904 (Box 1, Ledger 2)
  - City: Notices, Board of Councilmen Resolutions, etc, 1903-1914 (Box 1.1, Item 1-5)
  - City: Notices, Resolutions regarding sidewalks, curbs, gutters and other city works, 1915-1918 (Box 1.2, Item 1-3)
  - City & Town: Notices, Resolutions, etc., 1919-1948 (Box 1.3, Item 1-2)
    1919; Notices, Resolutions regarding sidewalks, etc.
    Town 1921 - 1948; Resolutions regarding budgets, Leases, VFD, Veteran's Bonds, Bills of Sale, etc
- Series II: City Clerk - Correspondence, 1897-1906
  Acc #180-1976
  Scope and Contents note
  The City Clerk's Office is the major records repository for the City of Danbury. All of the official business of the City is kept in this office. Although this is a small collection, the correspondence gives insight into the wide variety of business that was conducted during the given time period.
  - Correspondence A - C, 1903-1905 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence City Clerk, 1897-1899 (Box 2, Folder 2'-4)
  - Correspondence D - L, 1902-1906 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence M - N, 1903-1905 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence P - Z, 1901-1906 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Project for Sewers, Drains and Treatment Plant., 1934 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Stamped "approved" by the Federal Public Works Administration. Bid made by Sanborn and Bogert Consulting Engineers, NYC.
- Series III: Tax Anticipation Notes, 1933
  Acc #119-1976
  - City of Danbury Taxpayers' Anticipation Notes, Series II A, May 1, 1933 (Box 3, Ledger 1)
  - City of Danbury Taxpayers' Anticipation Notes, Series II B, June 1, 1933 (Box 3, Ledger 2)
  - City of Danbury Taxpayers' Anticipation Notes, Series II C, July 1, 1933 (Box 3, Ledger 3)
  - City of Danbury Taxpayers' Anticipation Notes, Series III A, May 1, 1933 (Box 3, Ledger 4)
  - City of Danbury Taxpayers' Anticipation Notes, Series III B, June 1, 1933 (Box 3, Ledger 5)
  - City of Danbury Taxpayers' Anticipation Notes, Series III C, July 1, 1933 (Box 3, Ledger 6)
- Series IV: Miscellaneous
  - Voter List?, 1967 (Box 3, Ledger 1)
    Small leather bound ledger from March 1967.
  - City of Danbury Auditor's Reports, 1937, 1938, 1941 - 1944, 1945 - 1946 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
    F3, F4 & F5 are joint accounts for Town and City